[MUSIC]
[背景音乐] 翻译: RyukaSuu |审阅: 19waa Coursera Global Translator Community
In this module, Emily covered various techniques for retrieving documents,
在这个模块里艾米莉 (Emily) 涵盖了用来检索文件和
exploring representations for a data like word count and TFIDF.
研究数据表达的多种技术 比如单词统计和TFIDF(词频-逆向文档频率)
Now we're gonna get a really cool Notebook where we put these ideas together and
现在 整合这些想法 我们将得到一个非常酷的Notebook
build a document retrieval system.
并且将使用TF-IDF技术
Using TFIDF.
建立一个文档恢复系统
So, let's go ahead and do just that.
所以 让我们动手做这些吧
As usual, we're gonna be using Python Notebook and
像往常一样 我们将使用iPython Notebook
in this one I'm gonna change the title to Document
这一次 我要把标题改为"Document retrieval (文档恢复)"
retrieval, and here we go.
这样就好了
And again, as usual, I'm gonna hide the header.
还是像往常一样 我将隐藏标题栏和工具栏
And hide the toolbar to give us a little bit more space.
从而多给我们一点空间
Okay, let's go ahead and fire up GraphLab Create.
好的 让我们来启用GraphLab Create
So we're gonna do import graphlab
所以我们要写 "import graphlab"
since we're gonna be using it again in our notebook.
因为我们会在我们的Notebook中再次用到它
Now the first step we're going to load some data.
现在 我们要做的第一步是导入一些数据
So let's Load some text data.
让我们导入一些文本数据
This is interesting text data from Wikipedia,
这是一份有趣的文本数据 它来自维基百科 (Wikipedia)
and it's pages on people.
它是一些关于人物的页面
So, cool data set and I'm just going to load it, and
很酷的数据 我即将导入它
we're going to see People which is gonna be an s frame
我们会用到变量people 这是一个SFrame
is gonna be graphlab.SFrame from a file and
它等于graphlab.SFrame
that file is called people wiki, right here.
来自名为 "people_wiki" 的文件 就在这里
And Here we go, we're loading it.
这样就可以了 我们正在导入它
And the first thing that we're gonna do is just look at a few top lines of that file.
我们首先要做的是看这个文件的最初几行
So I'm just gonna go ahead and you should see we have,
我继续操作 你们应该能看到
so this URI is basically the location of that page on Wikipedia.
所以这个URI基本上就是这个页面在维基百科 (Wikipedia) 上的位置
This is the name of the person involved.
这是相关人物的名字
and the text of that page about that person.
这是该人物页面上的文本
And you have this for a pretty nice number of people here.
并且你可以在这里找到相当多的人的数据
So if you type len of people.
如果你键入len(people) 显示长度
In our data set.
在我们这个数据集下
And type enter you see that we are talking about 59,000 people in this data set.
并敲下回车 你看我们所谈论的这个数据集中约有5万9千人
It's a pretty good set and
这是个不错的数据集
you will see with DFIF we are going to do some really interesting documents.
并且你将看到 我们要用TFIDF技术来处理一些十分有趣的文件
Even in this relatively large data set.
甚至这种相对较大的数据集
So the first thing we are going to do is just explore our data.
我们要做的第一件事就是浏览数据
So let's #Explore the dataset and
所以让我们浏览数据集并
checkout the text it contains.
查看它包含的文本
So let's start looking at a particular person dataset.
让我们开始具体关注某一个人的数据集
And we're gonna look at the page for
我们将看到
Barack Obama who is the current US President.
美国现任总统巴拉克·奥巴马 (Barack Obama) 的页面
So out of this people s-frame I'm going to select the one whose name,
从这些人的s-frame中 我将选择姓名为...
so that's the name column, is equal
这一列是姓名栏
to Barack Obama.
姓名为巴拉克·奥巴马 (Barack Obama) 的那一项
And so I pressed enter, and I created this new variable called Obama.
然后我敲下回车键 我就创建了一个名为Obama的新变量
And if you take a quick look at it, you see [COUGH] That it has the URL for
如果你大略扫一眼 就会看到它含有奥巴马 (Obama) 页面的网址
the Obama page, the name Barack Obama, and the text for that page.
巴拉克·奥巴马 (Barack Obama) 的名字 以及该页面中的文本
So let's dig in, and see what that text looks like.
然后让我们进一步深入 看看这个文本是什么样的
So for Barack Obama, you'll see that
关于巴拉克·奥巴马 (Barack Obama) 你将会看到
Barack Hussein Obama was born on August 4th, 1961, and
"巴拉克·侯赛因·奥巴马 (Barack Hussein Obama) 出生于1961年8月4日"
is the 44th The current President of the United States.
"现为第44届美国总统"
So pretty natural text will really expect for this kind of data.
该文本很符合我们对这种数据的预期
So we can also look at some other personal data set.
然后我们还可以看看其他人的数据集
So for example,
举例来说，
there's an actor called George Clooney who's been in a lot of movies.
这里有个名叫乔治·克鲁尼 (George Clooney) 的演员 他出演过很多电影
So if you look at the people As frame we're gonna select,
看这个people SFrame 我们将选择...
so this is again a filter operation which we've been doing almost every network now.
当然这也是一个我们现在几乎随处使用的筛选操作
Whose name is George Clooney?
我们选择名为乔治·克鲁尼 (George Clooney) 的那一项
And then I'm just gonna go ahead and
然后我将继续
show you the text that we get for George Clooney.
向你这是我们得到的 有关乔治·克鲁尼 (George Clooney) 的文本
And you see that George Timothy Clooney was born in 1961.
你会看到乔治·蒂莫西·克鲁尼 (George Timothy Clooney) 出生于1961年
So, basically, he's the same age as Barack Obama, but he's not president.
所以 大致来讲他和巴拉克·奥巴马 (Barack Obama) 同龄 但他不是总统
He's an American actor, writer.
他是一个美国演员、作家、
Producer, director
制作人、导演以及
and activist,
活动家
right here.
就在这儿
[MUSIC]
[背景音乐] 翻译: RyukaSuu |审阅: 19waa Coursera Global Translator Community